<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Track Awesome Integration Updates Weekly</title>
  <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/stn1slv/awesome-integration/week/feed.xml</id>
  <updated>2025-07-06T09:33:26.000Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/stn1slv/awesome-integration/week/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="application/json" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/stn1slv/awesome-integration/week/feed.json"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/stn1slv/awesome-integration/week/"/>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/bcomnes/jsonfeed-to-atom#readme" version="1.2.2">jsonfeed-to-atom</generator>
  <icon>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/icon.png</logo>
  <subtitle>A curated list of awesome system integration software and resources.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/27/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jul 07 - Jul 13, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-06T09:33:26.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-01T02:10:47.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Design</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apicurio/apicurio-studio" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apicurio Studio (⭐1k) (⭐1k)</a> - A web-based, open-source API design tool that leverages the OpenAPI specification.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/OpenAPITools/openapi-style-validator" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenAPI Style Validator (⭐218) (⭐218)</a> - Ensure that your OpenAPI specs meet your organization's standards with this flexible and customizable style validator.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Documentation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/DapperDox/dapperdox" rel="noopener noreferrer">DapperDox (⭐420) (⭐420)</a> - Generates elegant, interactive API documentation from OpenAPI/Swagger specs with easy customization and automated updates.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/shenyu" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache ShenYu (⭐8.6k) (⭐8.6k)</a> - A Java-native gateway excelling in protocol conversion, service proxying, and comprehensive API governance.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/envoyproxy/gateway" rel="noopener noreferrer">Envoy Gateway (⭐1.9k) (⭐2k)</a> - CNCF Envoy-based gateway with Gateway API, mTLS, JWT, and other built-ins.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / BRE</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/gorules/zen" rel="noopener noreferrer">ZEN Engine (⭐1.1k) (⭐1.2k)</a> - A cross-platform, open-source Business Rules Engine written in Rust that executes JSON Decision Models through interconnected graphs of decision tables, functions, and expressions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / CDC</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/debezium/debezium" rel="noopener noreferrer">Debezium (⭐11k) (⭐12k)</a> - Open-source distributed platform for change data capture that turns your existing databases into event streams for real-time data integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/infosphere-change-data-capture" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM InfoSphere CDC</a> - Enterprise CDC solution that captures and delivers data changes with minimal impact on source systems and low latency.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/zendesk/maxwell" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maxwell's daemon (⭐4.1k) (⭐4.2k)</a> - An open-source CDC tool for MySQL that reads database binlogs and streams row-level changes as JSON to systems like Kafka, Kinesis, or other destinations.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/integration/goldengate/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle GoldenGate</a> - Enterprise-grade real-time data integration and replication solution that provides comprehensive CDC capabilities for heterogeneous databases and cloud platforms.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.qlik.com/us/products/qlik-replicate" rel="noopener noreferrer">Qlik Replicate</a> - Universal data replication software that provides real-time CDC capabilities for modern data architecture and analytics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / ESB</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/wso2/product-ei" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Enterprise Integrator (⭐384) (⭐384)</a> - API-centric, cloud-native integration platform offering robust, distributed capabilities for modern software architectures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / ETL</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/inlong" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache InLong (⭐1.4k) (⭐1.4k)</a> - One-stop, full-scenario integration framework for massive data that supports data ingestion, synchronization, and subscription with real-time ETL capabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/nifi" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache NiFi (⭐5.4k) (⭐5.5k)</a> - Automated data integration tool with a visual interface that seamlessly extracts, transforms, and delivers data across systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.fivetran.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fivetran</a> - Managed ELT that syncs 700 + sources to data warehouses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Integration Frameworks</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/frankframework/frankframework" rel="noopener noreferrer">Frank!Framework (⭐141) (⭐141)</a> - Low-code Java messaging framework that simplifies system connectivity and data integration through configurable XML setups.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MaaS</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/event-hubs/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Event Hubs</a> - A high-throughput, fully managed event-ingestion (publish-subscribe) service, supports the Kafka protocol natively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MFT</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.jscape.com/products/file-transfer-servers/jscape-mft-server" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSCAPE MFT Server</a> - Secure, protocol-agnostic platform with automation and compliance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / RPA</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/open-rpa/openrpa" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenRPA (⭐2.6k) (⭐2.6k)</a> - Enterprise-grade, open-source robotic process automation suite.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/robotframework/robotframework" rel="noopener noreferrer">Robot Framework (⭐10k) (⭐11k)</a> - An open-source automation framework with human-friendly keyword syntax that enables both technical and non-technical users to create test scripts and automate business processes cost-effectively, supporting web, API, mobile, and database automation through extensive libraries and integrations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bonitasoft/bonita-engine" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bonita (⭐167) (⭐167)</a> - Open-source BPMN engine with a designer interface to build and automate complex business processes.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/flowable/flowable-engine" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flowable (⭐8.5k) (⭐8.5k)</a> - Compact, efficient set of open-source engines for automating and scaling enterprise workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Data Formats</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/avro" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Avro (⭐3.1k) (⭐3.1k)</a> - Data serialization system that provides compact, fast, and efficient serialization of structured data. It supports schema evolution, allows for efficient data compression, and is designed to work well with big data processing frameworks.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/27/"/>
    <summary>23 awesome projects updated on Jul 07 - Jul 13, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/26/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jun 30 - Jul 06, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-29T10:07:23.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-29T09:46:48.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / iPaaS</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.tibco.com/products/tibco-cloud-integration-ipaas" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Integration</a> - Flexible, API-led and event-driven platform that empowers you to integrate virtually any system quickly.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MDM</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tibco.com/products/ebx" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO EBX</a> - Comprehensive platform for governing and managing shared data assets, ensuring consistency and enabling smarter decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nsqio/nsq" rel="noopener noreferrer">NSQ (⭐25k) (⭐25k)</a> - Realtime distributed messaging platform designed to operate at scale, handling billions of messages per day with decentralized topology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://education.oracle.com/oracle-cloud-infrastructure-2024-application-integration-professional/pexam_1Z0-1042-25" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Cloud Platform Application Integration 2025 Certified Professional</a> - Validate your understanding of Oracle Application Integration to implement these Cloud services.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-businessworks" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BusinessWorks Associate</a> - Checks the understanding of Business Studio and TIBCO Cloud Integration, designing application components (modules, WSDL, REST API), developing integration applications, and testing, deploying, and managing applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-businessworks" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BusinessWorks Certified Professional</a> - Validates the ability to design, develop, deploy, monitor, and manage TIBCO BusinessWorks applications of average complexity with minimal supervision.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-businessworks-container-edition" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BusinessWorks Container Edition Certified Professional</a> - Validates the ability to develop, deploy, and manage TIBCO BusinessWorks Container Edition applications of average complexity with minimal supervision.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-bpm-enterprise" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BPM Enterprise Associate</a> - Checks the understanding of TIBCO BPM's features and capabilities, developing and managing business processes, and deploying and testing process applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-bpm-enterprise" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BPM Enterprise Certified Professional</a> - Validates the ability to design, develop, deploy, and manage business processes using TIBCO BPM Enterprise Suite.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-cloud" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Associate Certification</a> - Validates the skills and knowledge required to work with TIBCO Cloud, including its key components and features.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-cloud-api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud API Management Associate</a> - Covers topics such as API definition creation and testing, API key authentication, and using the Developer Portal and I/O docs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-cloud-api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud API Management Certified Professional</a> - Validates the ability to implement TIBCO Cloud Mesh, OAuth-based security, and manage SOAP services.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-cloud-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Integration Associate</a> - Validates the skills and knowledge required to work with TIBCO Cloud Integration, including its Connect, Develop, and Integrate capabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-cloud-integration-connect" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Integration - Connect Associate</a> - Checks the usage of Connect capability of TIBCO Cloud Integration, installing On-Premise Agent, creating connections and integration apps, and configuring flows.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-cloud-integration-connect" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Integration - Connect Certified Professional</a> - Checks the creation and management of connections, ensuring connection security, and troubleshooting issues related to connections in TIBCO Cloud Integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-cloud-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Cloud Integration Certified Professional</a> - Checks the knowledge about capabilities and benefits, integrating, developing, and connecting applications, creating APIs using the API Modeler and Mock functionality, and more.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tca-tibco-messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Messaging Associate</a> - Covers topics such as TIBCO Enterprise Message Service (EMS), TIBCO FTL, TIBCO eFTL, as well as other messaging technologies such as Apache Kafka, Apache Pulsar, and Eclipse Mosquitto.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.credly.com/org/citrix/badge/tcp-tibco-messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Messaging Certified Professional</a> - Validates the skills and knowledge required to work with TIBCO Messaging and its components, including TIBCO Enterprise Message Service (EMS), TIBCO FTL, and TIBCO eFTL.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/26/"/>
    <summary>18 awesome projects updated on Jun 30 - Jul 06, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/25/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jun 23 - Jun 29, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-21T01:22:08.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-21T01:22:08.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Design</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/OpenAPITools/openapi-generator" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenAPI Generator (⭐24k) (⭐24k)</a> - Automate the creation of API client libraries, server stubs, documentation and config files with this powerful OpenAPI Spec tool.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / BRE</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/openl-tablets/openl-tablets" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenL Tablets (⭐172) (⭐172)</a> - Flexible open-source decision management system that simplifies defining and executing business rules and decision tables.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/qpid-broker-j" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Qpid (⭐59) (⭐59)</a> - AMQP-compliant messaging tool with multi-language support for enterprise-grade message delivery.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/25/"/>
    <summary>3 awesome projects updated on Jun 23 - Jun 29, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/24/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jun 16 - Jun 22, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:55:47.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:55:47.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Kong/kong" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kong API Gateway (⭐41k) (⭐41k)</a> - A scalable, cloud-native gateway that simplifies API management through extensive plugin support and seamless microservices integration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/centrifugal/centrifugo" rel="noopener noreferrer">Centrifugo (⭐9k) (⭐9.1k)</a> - Scalable real-time messaging server that minimizes delay in delivering events to online users.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/eclipse/mosquitto" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eclipse Mosquitto (⭐9.8k) (⭐9.9k)</a> - Lightweight MQTT broker optimized for low-power devices with robust encryption and authentication.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/uber/cadence" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cadence (⭐8.7k) (⭐8.8k)</a> - Fault-tolerant, stateful platform that reliably orchestrates long-running workflows and complex applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elsa-workflows/elsa-core" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elsa Core (⭐7.1k) (⭐7.2k)</a> - .NET Core library that integrates seamlessly into any application to execute and manage workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Data Formats</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/yaml/yaml-spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">YAML (⭐399) (⭐399)</a> - A human-friendly and easy-to-read data serialization format that is widely used for configuration files and data exchange. It supports rich data types and is compatible with most programming languages.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/24/"/>
    <summary>6 awesome projects updated on Jun 16 - Jun 22, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/23/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jun 09 - Jun 15, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:55:27.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:55:27.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/cloudevents/spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">CloudEvents (⭐5.4k) (⭐5.4k)</a> -  A specification for describing event data in common formats to provide interoperability across services, platforms and systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/23/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Jun 09 - Jun 15, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/22/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jun 02 - Jun 08, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:54:22.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:54:22.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Documentation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rapi-doc/RapiDoc" rel="noopener noreferrer">RapiDoc (⭐1.8k) (⭐1.8k)</a> - Produces highly customizable, interactive API documentation with responsive design and rich configuration options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Testing</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mocking tools<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SpectoLabs/hoverfly" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hoverfly (⭐2.4k) (⭐2.4k)</a> - A lightweight API simulation tool that enables rapid HTTP(S) service virtualization for efficient testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/outofcoffee/imposter" rel="noopener noreferrer">Imposter (⭐391) (⭐391)</a> - A flexible mock server supporting REST, OpenAPI, SOAP, and more to simulate diverse API behaviors.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/microcks/microcks" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microcks (⭐1.6k) (⭐1.7k)</a> - A Kubernetes-native tool for API mocking and testing that supports AsyncAPI, OpenAPI, and Postman Collections.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.mockable.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mockable</a> - An easy-to-configure service for creating custom HTTP responses, ideal for rapid prototyping and testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/zuplo/mockbin" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mockbin (⭐113) (⭐113)</a> - A simple endpoint generator for testing HTTP requests with real-time logging and feedback.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mockoon/mockoon" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mockoon (⭐7.4k) (⭐7.5k)</a> - A user-friendly tool for designing and running mock REST APIs with real-time simulation and easy setup.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mock-server/mockserver" rel="noopener noreferrer">MockServer (⭐4.7k) (⭐4.8k)</a> - A powerful solution for mocking any HTTP/HTTPS-based service, streamlining integration testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/MockyAbstract/Mocky" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mocky (⭐2k) (⭐2.1k)</a> - A free online service that generates custom HTTP responses for testing API endpoints.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/stoplightio/prism" rel="noopener noreferrer">Prism (⭐4.6k) (⭐4.6k)</a> - An open-source HTTP mock server that replicates API behavior for early testing and validation.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tomakehurst/wiremock" rel="noopener noreferrer">WireMock (⭐6.8k) (⭐6.9k)</a> - A robust and flexible API mocking tool delivering reliable, real-time simulation for comprehensive testing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/azkaban/azkaban" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azkaban (⭐4.5k) (⭐4.5k)</a> - Distributed scheduler that simplifies managing job dependencies in large-scale data processing environments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Structure and Validation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/json-schema-org/json-schema-spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSON Schema (⭐4.3k) (⭐4.4k)</a> - A powerful tool for validating the structure of JSON data. JSON Schema enables developers to ensure that JSON data conforms to a specific structure, making it easier to process and manipulate.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/22/"/>
    <summary>4 awesome projects updated on Jun 02 - Jun 08, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/21/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 26 - Jun 01, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T00:54:35.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-21T00:54:35.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/temporalio/temporal" rel="noopener noreferrer">Temporal (⭐14k) (⭐15k)</a> - Open-source workflow-as-code platform designed for building reliable, scalable, and fault-tolerant applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/21/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on May 26 - Jun 01, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/20/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 19 - May 25, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T00:53:49.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T10:49:07.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / ETL</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pentaho/pentaho-kettle" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pentaho Data Integration (⭐8k) (⭐8.1k)</a> - Intuitive, visual ETL tool that simplifies data ingestion, blending, and cleansing across multiple sources without heavy coding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vernemq/vernemq" rel="noopener noreferrer">VerneMQ (⭐3.3k) (⭐3.4k)</a> - High-performance distributed MQTT broker designed for scalable and efficient message delivery in modern environments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/airflow" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Airflow (⭐40k) (⭐41k)</a> - Platform for programmatically creating, scheduling, and monitoring workflows, ideal for managing complex data pipelines.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://learn.snaplogic.com/snaplogic-accreditation" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Integrator Accreditation</a> - It's designed for those who want to enhance their expertise on all core SnapLogic concepts for various integration needs across industries and lines of business.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/20/"/>
    <summary>4 awesome projects updated on May 19 - May 25, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/19/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 12 - May 18, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T18:57:48.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-07T00:53:33.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/kafka" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Kafka (⭐30k) (⭐30k)</a> - Distributed, high-throughput system designed for real-time data streaming and fault-tolerant processing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/camunda/camunda-bpm-platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Camunda (⭐4.2k) (⭐4.2k)</a> - Flexible workflow and decision automation platform designed for scalable business process management.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/asyncapi/spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">AsyncAPI (⭐4.6k) (⭐4.7k)</a> - An essential tool for developing Event-Driven Architectures (EDA) and enables engineers to build a better tooling ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/19/"/>
    <summary>3 awesome projects updated on May 12 - May 18, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/18/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 05 - May 11, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:53:05.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:53:05.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/devopsfaith/krakend-ce" rel="noopener noreferrer">KrakenD API Gateway (⭐2.2k) (⭐2.3k)</a> - An ultra-high performance gateway with efficient middleware configuration, robust security, and seamless scaling.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / ETL</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/airbytehq/airbyte" rel="noopener noreferrer">Airbyte (⭐18k) (⭐19k)</a> - Flexible, open-source data integration platform that builds ELT pipelines to move data from diverse sources to modern destinations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nats-io/gnatsd" rel="noopener noreferrer">NATS (⭐17k) (⭐17k)</a> - Lightweight, high-performance messaging system ideal for microservices and cloud-native architectures.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/18/"/>
    <summary>3 awesome projects updated on May 05 - May 11, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/17/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 28 - May 04, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-04-23T00:52:13.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-23T00:52:13.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / BRE</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/incubator-kie-drools" rel="noopener noreferrer">Drools (⭐6k) (⭐6.1k)</a> - Open-source engine that supports advanced Decision Model and Notation (DMN) with Eclipse IDE integration for efficient rule development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/PrefectHQ/prefect" rel="noopener noreferrer">Prefect (⭐19k) (⭐20k)</a> - Modern, developer-friendly orchestration tool optimized for data pipelines and complex workflows.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/17/"/>
    <summary>2 awesome projects updated on Apr 28 - May 04, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/16/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 21 - Apr 27, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-04-16T00:52:37.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:52:37.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Design</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/stoplightio/spectral" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spectral (⭐2.7k) (⭐2.8k)</a> - Detect and fix errors in your JSON/YAML files using this linter tool that supports OpenAPI 3.0 &amp; 2.0 and AsyncAPI.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Documentation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/stoplightio/elements" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stoplight Elements (⭐2k) (⭐2.1k)</a> - Provides modular, attractive UI components for building comprehensive API reference and tutorial documentation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/apisix" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache APISIX (⭐15k) (⭐15k)</a> - A high-performance, dynamic gateway featuring real-time traffic management and powerful plugin integrations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Integration Frameworks</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/camel" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Camel (⭐5.8k) (⭐5.9k)</a> - Robust integration framework leveraging Enterprise Integration Patterns to seamlessly connect diverse systems and APIs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/standard-webhooks/standard-webhooks" rel="noopener noreferrer">Standard Webhooks (⭐1.4k) (⭐1.5k)</a> - Open source tools and guidelines for sending webhooks easily, securely, and reliably.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/16/"/>
    <summary>5 awesome projects updated on Apr 21 - Apr 27, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/15/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 14 - Apr 20, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-04-09T00:50:46.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-09T00:50:46.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / Data Mapping Solution</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bazaarvoice/jolt" rel="noopener noreferrer">JOLT (⭐1.6k) (⭐1.6k)</a> - Java-based JSON transformation library that uses a specification-driven approach for effortless JSON-to-JSON conversions.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/15/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Apr 14 - Apr 20, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/14/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 07 - Apr 13, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-04-02T00:51:17.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:51:17.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/eolinker/apinto" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apinto (⭐1.5k) (⭐1.6k)</a> - A Golang-based gateway that offers dynamic routing, multi-tenancy, and robust API access control for modern architectures.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/TykTechnologies/tyk" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tyk API Gateway (⭐10k) (⭐10k)</a> - An enterprise-grade, open-source gateway supporting REST, GraphQL, TCP, and gRPC with advanced rate limiting and analytics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/StackStorm/st2" rel="noopener noreferrer">StackStorm (⭐6.2k) (⭐6.3k)</a> - Robust automation engine that combines sensors, triggers, and workflows to orchestrate complex IT processes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Data Formats</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/protocolbuffers/protobuf" rel="noopener noreferrer">Protocol Buffers (⭐67k) (⭐68k)</a> - A language-neutral and platform-neutral serialization mechanism that is designed to be highly efficient and extensible. It supports rich data types and is widely used in distributed systems, such as gRPC and Apache Kafka.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/14/"/>
    <summary>4 awesome projects updated on Apr 07 - Apr 13, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/13/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Mar 31 - Apr 06, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-03-26T00:50:06.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-26T00:50:06.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / BRE</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ddossot/NxBRE" rel="noopener noreferrer">NxBRE (⭐132) (⭐132)</a> - Specialized .NET open-source rule engine offering efficient rule processing tailored for Microsoft environments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Protocols</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/openmessaging/specification" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenMessaging (⭐290) (⭐290)</a> - A cloud native, vendor-neutral open specification for distributed messaging.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/13/"/>
    <summary>2 awesome projects updated on Mar 31 - Apr 06, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/12/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Mar 24 - Mar 30, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-03-19T00:49:58.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T00:49:58.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ThreeMammals/Ocelot" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ocelot (⭐8.5k) (⭐8.6k)</a> - A .NET-based gateway offering intuitive routing and easy integration for lightweight API management.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/12/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Mar 24 - Mar 30, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/10/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Mar 10 - Mar 16, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-03-09T14:13:05.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-09T14:13:05.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Management</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.akana.com/products/api-platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Akana API Management Platform</a> - Provides comprehensive lifecycle management, enabling rapid digital transformation and robust compliance across multi-cloud environments.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/api-gateway/api-management/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon API Management</a> - Leverages AWS scalability and security to efficiently create, monitor, and manage APIs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/platform/api/manager" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anypoint Platform</a> - Combines API design, integration, and management into one unified platform, streamlining connectivity and development.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.axway.com/en/products/amplify-api-management-platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amplify API Management Platform</a> - Offers an open, agile approach to API management with robust integration and flexible deployment options.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apigee</a> - Delivers powerful analytics, security, and scalability for enterprise-grade API management from Google.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/api-management/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure API Management</a> - A hybrid, multicloud solution that simplifies API lifecycle management with comprehensive security and analytics.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.mashery.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Boomi Cloud API Management</a> - A cloud-native platform enabling seamless API deployment and centralized management with strong integration capabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.torryharris.com/products/digitmarket-api-manager-for-api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">DigitMarket API Manager</a> - Transforms APIs into strategic business tools through end-to-end lifecycle management and enhanced operational insights.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/api-connect" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM API Connect</a> - Provides a scalable, secure, and intuitive environment for creating, managing, and monetizing APIs across clouds.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/webmethods-api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM webMethods API Management</a> - Offers a comprehensive suite for API lifecycle management that seamlessly integrates on-premises and cloud systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://konghq.com/products/kong-enterprise" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kong Enterprise</a> - A cloud-native, enterprise-grade solution that enhances API connectivity, microservices orchestration, and security via a rich plugin architecture.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.broadcom.com/products/software/api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">Layer7 API Management</a> - Ensures secure and efficient API development with continuous lifecycle management and advanced integration features.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/jboss-middleware/3scale" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat 3scale API Management</a> - Simplifies API monetization and governance with a cloud-native approach and powerful scaling capabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sensedia.com/api-management-platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sensedia API Management</a> - Provides a full-lifecycle API solution with advanced security, performance monitoring, and streamlined integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://tyk.io/api-lifecycle-management/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tyk API Management</a> - Delivers high-performance, open-source API management focused on flexibility, robust security, and scalability.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://zuplo.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zuplo API Management</a> - A developer-centric, lightweight platform featuring GitOps integration, rapid edge deployment, extensive OpenAPI support, and seamless monetization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Documentation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Redocly/redoc" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redoc (⭐24k) (⭐25k)</a> - Delivers clean, modern documentation with advanced theming, multi-language support, and seamless integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/slatedocs/slate" rel="noopener noreferrer">Slate (⭐36k) (⭐36k)</a> - Converts markdown into stylish, static API documentation with intuitive navigation and clear code examples.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://swagger.io/tools/swaggerhub/" rel="noopener noreferrer">SwaggerHub</a> - An integrated API design and documentation hub that enhances team collaboration, version control, and automated testing.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui" rel="noopener noreferrer">Swagger UI (⭐27k) (⭐28k)</a> - Offers an interactive, in-browser tool for visualizing and testing APIs directly from OpenAPI specifications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/anvilco/spectaql" rel="noopener noreferrer">SpectaQL (⭐1.1k) (⭐1.2k)</a> - Generates static, customizable documentation for GraphQL schemas, making complex API structures easy to understand.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Gateway</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.getambassador.io/products/edge-stack/api-gateway/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ambassador Edge Stack</a> - A Kubernetes-native API gateway designed for high-scale environments with flexible routing and advanced security features.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/spring-cloud/spring-cloud-gateway" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spring Cloud Gateway (⭐4.6k) (⭐4.7k)</a> - Leverages the Spring ecosystem to deliver robust routing, filtering, and security for microservices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / API Testing</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>API clients<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/advanced-rest-client/arc-electron" rel="noopener noreferrer">Advanced REST Client (⭐1.4k) (⭐1.4k)</a> - A robust open-source API client for testing and debugging RESTful services with an intuitive interface.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/usebruno/bruno" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bruno (⭐35k) (⭐36k)</a> - A fast, offline API client designed for git-friendly workflows and seamless testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/curl/curl" rel="noopener noreferrer">curl (⭐38k) (⭐38k)</a> - A versatile command-line tool for data transfer across multiple protocols, essential for quick API testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rs/curlie" rel="noopener noreferrer">curlie (⭐3.3k) (⭐3.3k)</a> - A modern, user-friendly frontend to curl that combines simplicity with powerful performance.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/httpie/httpie" rel="noopener noreferrer">HTTPie (⭐36k) (⭐36k)</a> - An intuitive CLI HTTP client that simplifies crafting API requests and inspecting responses.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.httpmaster.net/" rel="noopener noreferrer">HttpMaster</a> - Free and lightweight desktop tool for HTTP testing and debugging.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hoppscotch/hoppscotch" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hoppscotch (⭐72k) (⭐73k)</a> - A lightweight, web-based API development tool offering real-time testing with an intuitive interface.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Kong/insomnia" rel="noopener noreferrer">Insomnia (⭐36k) (⭐37k)</a> - A cross-platform client that streamlines API debugging and testing for both REST and GraphQL services.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/darrenburns/posting" rel="noopener noreferrer">posting (⭐9.4k) (⭐9.4k)</a> - A modern, terminal-based API client designed for efficient and seamless API interactions.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.postman.com/product/api-client/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Postman</a> - The industry-standard tool for API development and testing, featuring automation, mock servers, and collaborative documentation.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/micha/resty" rel="noopener noreferrer">resty (⭐2.6k) (⭐2.7k)</a> - A Lua-based HTTP client framework providing an interactive shell for streamlined REST service testing.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SmartBear/soapui" rel="noopener noreferrer">SoapUI (⭐1.6k) (⭐1.6k)</a> - A comprehensive open-source solution for testing both SOAP and REST web services with extensive automation features.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Testing tools and frameworks<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/jmeter" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache JMeter (⭐8.8k) (⭐8.9k)</a> - A feature-rich tool for load testing and performance analysis across diverse web applications and services.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/gatling/gatling" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gatling (⭐6.7k) (⭐6.7k)</a> - A powerful load testing framework with a developer-friendly DSL that delivers detailed performance metrics.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/grafana/k6" rel="noopener noreferrer">Grafana k6 (⭐28k) (⭐28k)</a> - Open-source, JS-scriptable load-testing tool for CI/CD.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/karatelabs/karate" rel="noopener noreferrer">Karate (⭐8.5k) (⭐8.6k)</a> - A unified testing framework that merges API automation, mocking, and performance testing with simple, expressive syntax.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/svanoort/pyresttest" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pyresttest (⭐1.1k) (⭐1.2k)</a> - A Python-based testing tool offering easy YAML/JSON-driven REST API testing and microbenchmarking.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rest-assured/rest-assured" rel="noopener noreferrer">REST Assured (⭐6.9k) (⭐7k)</a> - A Java DSL that simplifies REST API testing with intuitive syntax and seamless integration into CI pipelines.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/schemathesis/schemathesis" rel="noopener noreferrer">Schemathesis (⭐2.5k) (⭐2.6k)</a> - A Python library for property-based testing of API schemas, ensuring reliability through robust edge-case detection.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Blazemeter/taurus" rel="noopener noreferrer">Taurus (⭐2k) (⭐2.1k)</a> - An open-source automation framework that simplifies continuous testing with intuitive configuration and integration support.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / BRE</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/j-easy/easy-rules" rel="noopener noreferrer">Easy Rules (⭐5k) (⭐5.1k)</a> - Lightweight Java-based rules engine designed for straightforward rule processing and rapid decision automation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.fico.com/en/products/fico-blaze-advisor" rel="noopener noreferrer">FICO Blaze Advisor</a> - Enterprise-grade decision engine that empowers both business and technical users with an intuitive interface for fast rule creation and management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/operational-decision-manager" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM ODM</a> - Scalable decision management system that streamlines rule authoring, testing, and updates while ensuring compliance and agility.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.progress.com/corticon" rel="noopener noreferrer">Progress Corticon</a> - Model-driven BRMS enabling rapid, no-code rule creation that delivers high-performance automated decisions with guaranteed integrity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://access.redhat.com/products/red-hat-decision-manager" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Decision Manager</a> - Enterprise-class decision platform built on Drools, offering advanced DMN support, intuitive UIs, and high availability for large-scale automation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / BPM</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://appian.com/platform/complete-automation/business-process-management-bpm.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Appian BPM Suite</a> - Low-code BPM platform that empowers both IT and citizen developers to quickly build process- and case-centric applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.genpact.com/cora/sequence" rel="noopener noreferrer">Genpack Cora SeQuence</a> - Agile process orchestration tool that enhances business efficiency by seamlessly integrating and managing workflows.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/business-automation-workflow" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Business Automation Workflow</a> - Integrated platform combining workflow automation and BPM to optimize operational processes and decision-making.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/middleware/technologies/bpm.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle BPM Suite</a> - Comprehensive solution offering robust process modeling, workflow automation, and real-time analytics to drive operational excellence.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.pega.com/products/platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pega Platform</a> - Advanced BPM and RPA platform featuring intelligent process automation and workforce analytics to streamline operations.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/jboss-middleware/process-automation-manager" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Process Automation Manager</a> - Cloud-native platform that enables cross-functional teams to design, deploy, and manage automated business workflows with agility.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sap.com/products/process-orchestration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAP Process Orchestration</a> - Robust BPM offering that combines process orchestration with application integration for end-to-end operational efficiency.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tibco.com/products/business-process-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BPM Enterprise</a> - Enterprise BPM solution delivering process automation, documentation, and predictive analytics to enhance performance and decision-making.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Data Mapping Solution</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.altova.com/mapforce" rel="noopener noreferrer">Altova MapForce</a> - Graphical data mapping solution that enables any-to-any conversion, reducing complexity and accelerating integration projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / ESB</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/platform/enterprise-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anypoint Platform</a> - Comprehensive integration solution that leverages robust ESB capabilities to connect and orchestrate disparate systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://servicemix.apache.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache ServiceMix</a> - Versatile open-source integration container combining messaging, routing, and service mediation for flexible enterprise connectivity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.arcesb.com/integration/" rel="noopener noreferrer">ArcESB</a> - Flexible integration platform that synchronizes data across applications, streamlines partner connectivity, and enhances data accessibility.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/app-connect" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM App Connect</a> - Robust integration solution that connects diverse applications and protocols, ensuring seamless data flow across the enterprise.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/webmethods-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM webMethods Integration</a> - Comprehensive platform that accelerates application integration and simplifies connectivity across heterogeneous systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Particular/NServiceBus" rel="noopener noreferrer">NServiceBus (⭐2.1k) (⭐2.1k)</a> - Developer-friendly, .NET-based service bus that simplifies messaging and orchestrates service integration efficiently.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/middleware/technologies/service-bus.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Service Bus</a> - Powerful ESB solution that virtualizes and manages service interactions to reduce integration complexity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/middleware/technologies/soasuite.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle SOA Suite</a> - Comprehensive SOA platform that orchestrates services into composite applications, driving efficient business process integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developers.redhat.com/products/fuse/overview" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Fuse</a> - Cloud-native integration platform that delivers distributed integration capabilities for agile, scalable connectivity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tibco.com/products/tibco-businessworks" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO BusinessWorks</a> - Enterprise-grade integration platform implementing proven hybrid integration patterns for reliable data exchange.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.adroitlogic.com/products/ultraesb/" rel="noopener noreferrer">UltraESB</a> - High-performance ESB engineered for extreme throughput with zero-copy proxying and non-blocking IO techniques.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / ETL</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.cloverdx.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">CloverDX</a> - Enterprise ETL suite offering robust data transformation and workflow orchestration for scalable integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://hevodata.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hevo</a> - No-code, fully automated data pipeline platform that supports extensive integrations, simplifying complex data workflows.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/datastage" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM DataStage</a> - Robust platform that cleanses, transforms, and delivers reliable data, empowering businesses with trusted insights.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.informatica.com/products/data-integration/powercenter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Informatica PowerCenter</a> - Enterprise-class solution that streamlines big data and cloud analytics through comprehensive data integration management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/integration-services/sql-server-integration-services" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft SSIS</a> - Proven data integration solution for building scalable ETL processes within enterprise environments using SQL Server.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/middleware/technologies/data-integrator.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Data Integrator</a> - Comprehensive platform that addresses batch loads, real-time processes, and SOA-enabled services for end-to-end data management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sas.com/en_us/software/data-management.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAS Data Management</a> - Robust solution that transforms, integrates, and secures data to enhance quality and reliability across the enterprise.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.stitchdata.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stitch</a> - Developer-friendly SaaS ETL service that effortlessly extracts data from numerous sources into data warehouses for streamlined analytics.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.talend.com/products/integrate-data/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Talend Data Integration</a> - Versatile platform that unifies disparate data sources into actionable insights to empower informed business decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Integration Frameworks</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ballerina-platform/ballerina-lang" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ballerina (⭐3.7k) (⭐3.8k)</a> - Innovative programming language designed for effortless creation and integration of network services and APIs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/spring-projects/spring-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spring Integration (⭐1.5k) (⭐1.6k)</a> - Extension of the Spring ecosystem that provides out-of-the-box integration capabilities using proven Enterprise Integration Patterns.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / iPaaS</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/platform/saas/cloudhub-ipaas-cloud-based-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anypoint Platform</a> - Combines API management and integration into one platform, enabling seamless connectivity across diverse applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://boomi.com/platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Boomi AtomSphere</a> - Cloud-native, intelligent platform that connects systems effortlessly while automating integration processes.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.celigo.com/platform/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Celigo Integration Platform</a> - User-friendly iPaaS with prebuilt templates for rapid SaaS-to-SaaS integrations and intuitive drag-and-drop design.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.jitterbit.com/platform/ipaas" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jitterbit Harmony</a> - Comprehensive integration solution offering prebuilt workflows and automation templates to accelerate business processes.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Cloud Integration</a> - Next-generation platform leveraging AI to streamline integration, increase scalability, and speed up deployment.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/webmethods" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM webMethods</a> - All-in-one integration platform that unifies applications, simplifies processes, and boosts overall efficiency.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.informatica.com/products/cloud-integration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Informatica Intelligent Cloud Services</a> - Suite of cloud data management tools that accelerates productivity and simplifies application and data integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://businessnetwork.opentext.com/enterprise-data-management/" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenText Alloy</a> - Enterprise data management solution that transforms basic integration into actionable insights and smarter decision-making.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/integration/application-integration/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Integration Cloud Service</a> - Robust platform with prebuilt connectivity for both SaaS and on-premises apps, streamlining integration processes.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sap.com/products/technology-platform/integration-suite.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAP Integration Suite</a> - Cloud-native solution offering prebuilt adapters, API management, and event brokering for end-to-end connectivity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.snaplogic.com/products/intelligent-integration-platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Intelligent Integration Platform</a> - AI-driven platform that connects applications and data rapidly, ensuring efficient and scalable integrations.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://tray.ai/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tray.io</a> - Low-code automation platform with a drag-and-drop interface, making it simple to build scalable integrations and workflows.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.workato.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Workato</a> - Unified integration and workflow automation solution that simplifies complex processes and enhances operational efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MaaS</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-mq" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MQ</a> - Fully managed message broker supporting Apache ActiveMQ and RabbitMQ, ensuring reliable and secure messaging.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon MSK</a> - Managed Apache Kafka service that simplifies cluster setup, scaling, and real-time data streaming.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sqs" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon SQS</a> - Reliable, fully managed queuing service to decouple microservices and scale distributed applications seamlessly.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sns" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon SNS</a> - Managed pub/sub messaging service that flexibly notifies subscribers and supports various delivery protocols.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/product/kafka" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alibaba Cloud Message Queue for Apache Kafka</a> - High-throughput Kafka service with seamless Alibaba Cloud integration for real-time data processing.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/product/rabbitmq" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alibaba Cloud Message Queue for RabbitMQ</a> - Scalable RabbitMQ solution offering low latency and high throughput for distributed messaging.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/product/message-service" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alibaba Cloud Message Service</a> - Distributed messaging service that ensures reliable data transfer between decoupled systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/product/mq" rel="noopener noreferrer">AlibabaMQ for Apache RocketMQ</a> - Robust message queue service supporting asynchronous communication with high availability and durability.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/platform/anypoint-mq-message-queue" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anypoint MQ</a> - Enterprise-class messaging service integrated with Anypoint Platform for flexible and reliable message orchestration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/service-bus/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Service Bus</a> - Cloud messaging solution that supports multiple patterns and protocols for robust enterprise integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.cloudamqp.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">CloudAMQP</a> - Managed RabbitMQ service featuring an intuitive web console, advanced analytics, and seamless scalability.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.confluent.io/confluent-cloud/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Confluent Cloud</a> - Fully managed Kafka service offering enterprise features like schema registry, connectors, and governance.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/managed-service-for-apache-kafka" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka</a> - Simplifies Kafka deployment and management on Google Cloud for real-time streaming applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/pubsub" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Cloud Pub/Sub</a> - High-throughput messaging service that supports event-driven architectures with flexible delivery models.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.huaweicloud.com/intl/en-us/product/dms.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Huawei Cloud Distributed Message Service</a> - Fully managed messaging service that ensures secure, scalable, and reliable communication between applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.huaweicloud.com/intl/en-us/product/dmskafka.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Huawei Cloud Distributed Message Service for Kafka</a> - Managed Kafka solution that simplifies scaling and management while delivering high performance and security.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/mq" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM MQ on Cloud</a> - Enterprise messaging service that offers secure, reliable data transfer across applications in a cloud environment.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.iron.io/mq" rel="noopener noreferrer">IronMQ</a> - Elastic, cloud-native message queue designed for scalable and reliable processing of high-volume messages.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/cloud/cloud-native/streaming/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Cloud Streaming</a> - Serverless, real-time event streaming platform with Apache Kafka compatibility for efficient data processing.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://solace.com/products/platform/cloud/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solace PubSub+ Cloud</a> - Integrated event streaming platform providing full visibility and control over your data pipelines.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.yandex.com/en/services/message-queue" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yandex Message Queue</a> - Cloud messaging service compatible with Amazon SQS API for easy integration with existing systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.yandex.com/en/services/managed-kafka" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yandex Managed Service for Apache Kafka</a> - Fully managed Kafka service with automated scaling, monitoring, and maintenance for hassle-free streaming.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MFT</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.arcesb.com/mft/" rel="noopener noreferrer">ArcESB Managed File Transfer</a> - Enterprise-grade MFT solution with an intuitive interface and powerful automation for streamlined file exchanges.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.axway.com/en/products/managed-file-transfer" rel="noopener noreferrer">Axway Managed File Transfer</a> - Robust platform offering advanced security and efficient, reliable data transfer across enterprise systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.goanywhere.com/products/goanywhere-mft" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoAnywhere MFT</a> - Comprehensive solution delivering centralized, secure file transfers with automation and complete audit logging.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.globalscape.com/eft" rel="noopener noreferrer">GlobalSCAPE EFT</a> - Hardened file transfer server that ensures end-to-end encryption, automation, and compliance for mission-critical data.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/secure-file-transfer" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Sterling Secure File Transfer</a> - Scalable and high-performance MFT platform designed for secure, fast, and reliable file exchange.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/webmethods-mft" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM webMethods MFT</a> - Integrated managed file transfer solution that supports flexible deployment across hybrid environments.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/middleware/technologies/mft/managed-file-transfer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Managed File Transfer</a> - Comprehensive platform that simplifies secure file exchange and management for enterprise operations.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.progress.com/moveit" rel="noopener noreferrer">Progress MOVEit</a> - Secure, automated file transfer solution with guaranteed delivery, encryption, and compliance tools for regulated industries.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tibco.com/products/tibco-managed-file-transfer" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Managed File Transfer</a> - Centralized MFT platform with robust automation and security features designed to support diverse file transfer scenarios.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://southrivertech.com/titan-mft-server/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Titan MFT Server</a> - Enterprise-level MFT server offering high availability, failover capabilities, and efficient large-scale file automation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / MDM</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/ibm-infosphere-master-data-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM InfoSphere Master Data Management</a> - Comprehensive platform that centralizes data governance, ensuring consistency and accuracy across your enterprise.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.informatica.com/products/master-data-management/multidomain-mdm.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Informatica Multidomain MDM</a> - Integrated solution for managing and governing master data across all domains, enhancing overall data quality.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/performance-management/enterprise-data-management/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Enterprise Data Management</a> - Robust tool that centralizes master data to support faster, more effective decision-making and operational agility.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reltio.com/products/multidomain-mdm" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reltio</a> - Cloud-native, multi-domain MDM platform combining data quality, governance, and real-time analytics for a 360° view.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.sap.com/products/master-data-governance.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAP Master Data Governance</a> - Centralized solution that consolidates and governs master data to ensure consistency and high quality.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://support.sas.com/en/software/mdm-support.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAS MDM</a> - Unified platform that integrates data from diverse sources into accurate master records for improved efficiency.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.stibosystems.com/platform" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stibo MDM</a> - Proven multi-domain MDM solution focusing on data transparency and governance to provide a single source of truth.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.teradata.co.uk/Products/Applications/Master-Data-Management" rel="noopener noreferrer">Teradata MDM</a> - Establishes a consistent analytical foundation by maintaining accurate reference data for enhanced ROI.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Messaging</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/activemq" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache ActiveMQ (⭐2.3k) (⭐2.4k)</a> - Open-source broker that implements JMS, enabling seamless conversion between synchronous and asynchronous messaging.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/pulsar" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache Pulsar (⭐14k) (⭐15k)</a> - Versatile pub/sub and streaming platform offering scalable, low-latency messaging for modern applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/rocketmq" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apache RocketMQ (⭐21k) (⭐22k)</a> - High-performance distributed messaging platform engineered for low latency and high throughput.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bloomberg/blazingmq" rel="noopener noreferrer">BlazingMQ (⭐2.6k) (⭐2.7k)</a> - Distributed message queuing system focused on efficiency and reliability for modern workflow needs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/products/mq" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM MQ</a> - Enterprise-grade messaging solution providing robust features, high availability, and multi-protocol support.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://kubemq.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer">KubeMQ</a> - Kubernetes-native message broker and queue system designed for scalability, high availability, and seamless cloud integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oracle.com/database/technologies/advanced-queuing.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle AQ</a> - Integrated messaging solution within Oracle databases, offering reliable and efficient message delivery.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rabbitmq/rabbitmq-server" rel="noopener noreferrer">RabbitMQ (⭐12k) (⭐13k)</a> - Popular open-source broker implementing AMQP, known for reliability, clustering, and ease-of-use.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vectorizedio/redpanda" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redpanda (⭐10k) (⭐11k)</a> - Kafka-compatible streaming platform that eliminates Zookeeper, delivering high performance and low latency.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/jboss-middleware/amq" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat AMQ</a> - Enterprise messaging platform based on open-source technologies, offering scalable and reliable message delivery.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tibco.com/products/tibco-enterprise-message-service" rel="noopener noreferrer">TIBCO Enterprise Message Service</a> - Standards-based JMS implementation that enables efficient and robust exchange of messages between applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / RPA</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.automationanywhere.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automation Anywhere</a> - Intelligent automation ecosystem that streamlines business processes and reduces errors through advanced RPA capabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.blueprism.com/products/intelligent-rpa-automation/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Blue Prism</a> - No-code platform delivering robust, scalable automation to minimize manual tasks and boost productivity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.tungstenautomation.com/products/rpa" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tungsten RPA</a> - AI-powered, no-code automation solution that enhances accuracy, efficiency, and compliance across workflows.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.uipath.com/product" rel="noopener noreferrer">UiPath</a> - Comprehensive RPA platform that automates routine tasks, enabling scalable digital transformation across enterprises.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.workfusion.com/platform/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WorkFusion</a> - Enterprise automation solution that combines RPA with intelligent automation to streamline complex workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Self-Service Integration</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ifttt.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">IFTTT</a> - Easy-to-use platform that connects web services with simple conditional statements, empowering custom workflow creation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.make.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">Make (Integromat)</a> - Low-code automation tool with a visual interface, advanced data transformation, and modular workflow execution.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://powerautomate.microsoft.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Power Automate</a> - Cloud-based service with an intuitive interface for creating automated workflows that seamlessly integrate diverse apps.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.oracle.com/en/cloud/paas/self-service-integration-cloud/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Self-Service Integration</a> - Streamlined tool that automates tasks between cloud applications, making integration accessible for non-developers.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://zapier.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zapier</a> - Intuitive platform that connects hundreds of web services to create efficient, code-free automations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Projects / Workflow engine</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Activiti/Activiti" rel="noopener noreferrer">Activiti (⭐10k) (⭐10k)</a> - Lightweight, Java-centric BPMN engine that efficiently executes business workflows with a focus on simplicity.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows" rel="noopener noreferrer">Argo Workflows (⭐15k) (⭐16k)</a> - Container-native workflow engine designed for orchestrating parallel jobs in Kubernetes-based, cloud-native environments.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Netflix/conductor" rel="noopener noreferrer">Conductor (⭐12k) (⭐13k)</a> - Cloud-based orchestration engine that manages microservices workflows, streamlining complex process automation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kiegroup/jbpm" rel="noopener noreferrer">jBPM (⭐1.6k) (⭐1.7k)</a> - Comprehensive toolkit for automating business processes and decisions with robust workflow management capabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/10/"/>
    <summary>139 awesome projects updated on Mar 10 - Mar 16, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/9/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Mar 03 - Mar 09, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T00:46:45.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-02-26T00:46:45.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Design</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apiaryio/dredd" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dredd (⭐4.2k) (⭐4.2k)</a> - Validate API description docs against backend implementation using this language-agnostic CLI tool.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/9/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Mar 03 - Mar 09, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/3/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jan 20 - Jan 26, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-01-15T00:45:05.000Z</updated>
    <published>2025-01-15T00:45:05.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/json-api/json-api" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSON:API (⭐7.5k) (⭐7.6k)</a> - A standardized specification for building APIs that simplifies the representation of resources, relationships, and metadata, making it easier for software engineers to create efficient APIs.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2025/3/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Jan 20 - Jan 26, 2025</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/46/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Nov 11 - Nov 17, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-13T00:44:48.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-11-13T00:44:48.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/OAI/OpenAPI-Specification" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenAPI (ex.Swagger) (⭐29k) (⭐30k)</a> - A language-agnostic specification for creating RESTful APIs that enables both humans and machines to understand the capabilities of a service without the need for source code or documentation.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/46/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Nov 11 - Nov 17, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/45/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Nov 04 - Nov 10, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T14:48:04.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-11-07T14:48:04.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apiacademy.learnupon.com/lpaths/4147453/courses/262369/details" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Designer</a> - Validate your understanding of API design basics and best practices.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://apiacademy.learnupon.com/lpaths/4147453/courses/262371/details" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Product Manager</a> - Demonstrate your proficiency in managing APIs as products.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://apiacademy.learnupon.com/lpaths/4147453/courses/262370/details" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Security Architect</a> - Validate your expertise in securing APIs using modern architectures.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/45/"/>
    <summary>3 awesome projects updated on Nov 04 - Nov 10, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/35/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Aug 26 - Sep 01, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-08-28T00:41:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-08-28T00:41:00.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Projects / API Design</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Mermade/openapi-gui" rel="noopener noreferrer">OpenAPI-GUI (⭐1.4k) (⭐1.5k)</a> - Create and validate OpenAPI specs with ease using this intuitive graphical user interface.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/35/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Aug 26 - Sep 01, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/20/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 13 - May 19, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-05-15T00:36:09.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-05-15T00:36:09.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Articles</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/shieldfy/API-Security-Checklist" rel="noopener noreferrer">API-Security-Checklist (⭐22k) (⭐23k)</a> - Best practices about REST API security.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/20/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on May 13 - May 19, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/17/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 22 - Apr 28, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T08:48:47.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-04-24T08:48:47.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apollographql.com/tutorials/exams/apollo-graph-associate" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apollo Graph Developer - Associate Certification</a> - Developers who obtain this certification possess a solid foundational knowledge of GraphQL and the Apollo tool suite to design a schema, run an Apollo Server 4, and perform queries with Apollo Client 3 on the frontend.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apollographql.com/tutorials/certifications/apollo-graph-professional" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apollo Graph Developer - Professional Certification</a> - Developers who obtain this certification demonstrate strong familiarity with Apollo Federation concepts. They can apply those concepts to build a federated supergraph or move an existing monolithic graph to federation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://learning.sap.com/certifications/sap-certified-associate-integration-developer" rel="noopener noreferrer">SAP Certified Associate - Integration Developer</a> - Validates that the candidate possesses the fundamental and core knowledge required of the SAP Integration Suite profile.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/17/"/>
    <summary>3 awesome projects updated on Apr 22 - Apr 28, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/9/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Feb 26 - Mar 03, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T08:35:34.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-02-29T08:35:34.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/api-documentation-best-practices" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Documentation Best Practices</a> - The 2-hour course covers everything you need to know to create, automate, and publish API documentation your developers, partners and users will love. You wll also learn why API documentation is the foundation for strong governance, effective API security, and achieving your API business goals.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/api-penetration-testing" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Penetration Testing</a> - The API Penetration Testing course covers all the key topics to become an APIsec professional. This hands-on course includes over 12 hours of live instruction and provides detailed labs on API hacking techniques and how to uncover vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/api-security-for-pci-compliance" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Security for PCI Compliance</a> - This 60-minute course examines the new PCI DSS 4.0 requirements and details the API security obligations for compliance. DSS 4.0 introduces API security concerns for the time ever - enroll to understand what the implications are for your organization.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/api-security-fundamentals" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Security Fundamentals</a> - The 90-minute course covers the core threats to APIs and how to prevent breaches. Learn the OWASP API Security Top 10, examine real-world API attacks, and understand the 3 Pillars of API Security.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/certified-api-security-analyst-exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">Certified API Security Analyst</a> - The CASA exam is designed to test your expertise in API security threats, risks, and best practices. Students are expected to have completed the OWASP API Security and Beyond! course before attempting to earn the CASA certification.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/owasp-api-security-top-10-and-beyond" rel="noopener noreferrer">OWASP API Security Top 10</a> - The 90-minute course provides a deep-dive into the 2023 edition of the OWASP API Security Top 10 - and covers key concepts that didn't make it into the Top 10.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apisecuniversity.com/courses/securing-api-servers" rel="noopener noreferrer">Securing API Servers</a> - Learn key concepts for keeping API servers secure - from CORS to error handling to rate limiting and more.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/9/"/>
    <summary>7 awesome projects updated on Feb 26 - Mar 03, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/7/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Feb 12 - Feb 18, 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-02-14T00:33:37.000Z</updated>
    <published>2024-02-14T00:33:37.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apiaryio/api-blueprint" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Blueprint (⭐8.6k) (⭐8.7k)</a> - A powerful high-level language for designing and documenting APIs that allows software engineers to easily collaborate and create efficient APIs.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2024/7/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Feb 12 - Feb 18, 2024</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/33/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Aug 14 - Aug 20, 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T18:17:31.000Z</updated>
    <published>2023-08-20T06:48:11.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/graphql/graphql-spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">GraphQL (⭐14k) (⭐14k)</a> - A sophisticated query language and runtime for building efficient APIs that empowers engineers to retrieve data from existing systems with ease.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/raml-org/raml-spec" rel="noopener noreferrer">RAML (⭐3.8k) (⭐3.9k)</a> - A RESTful API Modeling Language that allows software engineers to design and create efficient APIs by modeling resources, endpoints, and interactions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Data Formats</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/xml11/" rel="noopener noreferrer">XML</a> - A flexible and widely used markup language that is used for storing and exchanging structured data. It supports rich data types and is compatible with many programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Protocols</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://httpwg.org/specs/" rel="noopener noreferrer">HTTP</a> - A widely used protocol that facilitates communication between web servers and clients. HTTP enables the transfer of data over the internet, making it possible for web applications to function seamlessly.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/33/"/>
    <summary>4 awesome projects updated on Aug 14 - Aug 20, 2023</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/20/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 15 - May 21, 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T15:10:51.000Z</updated>
    <published>2023-05-15T08:01:34.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Articles</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ics.uci.edu/~fielding/pubs/dissertation/top.htm" rel="noopener noreferrer">Architectural Styles and
the Design of Network-based Software Architectures</a> - Roy Fielding's dissertation defining REST.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://pages.apigee.com/rs/apigee/images/api-design-ebook-2012-03.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer">Web API Design: Crafting interfaces that developers love</a> - Creating Web APIs that are consistent, intuitive, and user-friendly for developers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://academy.workato.com/enterprise-automation-i-exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">Workato Automation Pro I</a> - Fundamentals of business automation processes.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://academy.workato.com/enterprise-automation-ii-exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">Workato Automation Pro II</a> - Advanced and practical approaches to automation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://academy.workato.com/automation-pro-iii-exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">Workato Automation Pro III</a> - In-depth series of badged modules for maximizing Workato's potential.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-api-manager-developer/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified API Manager Developer - V3</a> - Assesses your expertise in designing, developing, and publishing APIs using WSO2 API Manager V3, including API lifecycle management, access control, and API documentation.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-api-manager-developer-v4-micro-integrator-profile/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified API Manager Developer - V4 - Micro Integrator Profile</a> - Validates your expertise in designing, developing, and publishing APIs using the Micro Integrator profile of WSO2 API Manager V4. It covers API lifecycle management, access control, and API documentation within the Micro Integrator context.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-api-manager-expert/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified API Manager Expert - V3</a> - Confirms your advanced skills and knowledge in using WSO2 API Manager V3 for API management, including API creation, publishing, security, policy implementation, and analytics.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/api-manager-expert-v4-api-management-profile/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified API Manager Expert - V4 - API Management Profile</a> - Demonstrates your proficiency in using WSO2 API Manager V4 for API management tasks, such as creating, publishing, and securing APIs, as well as implementing policies and analytics.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-enterprise-integrator-developer-micro-integrator/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified Enterprise Integrator Developer - V7 - Micro Integrator</a> - Validates your knowledge and skills in using the Micro Integrator profile of WSO2 Enterprise Integrator V7 to develop, deploy, and manage integration solutions.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-enterprise-integrator-developer-streaming-integrator/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified Enterprise Integrator Developer - V7 - Streaming Integrator</a> - Demonstrates your expertise in using the Streaming Integrator profile of WSO2 Enterprise Integrator V7 to develop, deploy, and manage real-time data integration and streaming analytics solutions.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-enterprise-integrator6-expert/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified Enterprise Integrator Expert - V6</a> - Tests your in-depth knowledge and skills in using WSO2 Enterprise Integrator V6 for complex integration scenarios, including best practices, troubleshooting, and performance tuning.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://wso2.com/training/certification/certified-solutions-architect-associate/" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSO2 Certified Solutions Architect Associate</a> - Assesses your understanding of the fundamental concepts and principles of WSO2 product architecture, as well as your ability to design and implement solutions using WSO2 technologies.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/20/"/>
    <summary>13 awesome projects updated on May 15 - May 21, 2023</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/19/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on May 08 - May 14, 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T15:32:22.000Z</updated>
    <published>2023-05-12T15:32:22.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Certifications</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIKWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Associate Administrator Certification</a> - Validates an individual's foundational knowledge and skills in managing and administering the Boomi platform, focusing on platform monitoring, troubleshooting, and security.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIeWAM&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Associate Developer Certification</a> - Demonstrates a candidate's basic understanding of building and deploying integration processes using the Boomi platform, including design patterns, deployment, and error handling.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIFWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Associate EDI for X12 Certification</a> - Validates an individual's proficiency in using Boomi to design, develop, and manage Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) integrations with the X12 standard, covering essential concepts like EDI document structure and trading partner management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIZWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Associate Flow Essentials Certification</a> - Showcases a candidate's knowledge of creating and managing business applications using Boomi Flow, with emphasis on workflow design, user interfaces, and data integration.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIPWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Associate Master Data Hub Certification</a> - Highlights a candidate's understanding of using the Boomi Master Data Hub to ensure data quality and consistency across systems, focusing on data modeling, governance, and synchronization.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OJOWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Development and Application Architecture Certification</a> - Confirms an individual's expertise in designing and implementing complex integration solutions and application architectures on the Boomi platform, including best practices and performance optimization.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OKzWAM&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional API Design Certification</a> - Demonstrates a candidate's ability to design, develop, and manage APIs using Boomi, including RESTful API principles, API security, and versioning.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIyWAM&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional API Management Certification</a> - Validates an individual's expertise in managing the full lifecycle of APIs using the Boomi platform, including API deployment, monitoring, and analytics.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OJrWAM&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional Developer Certification</a> - Recognizes a candidate's in-depth knowledge and skills in developing, deploying, and managing integration processes using Boomi, with emphasis on advanced data transformation and error handling techniques.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIUWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional Flow Developer Certification</a> - Showcases an individual's advanced capabilities in designing, developing, and managing business applications using Boomi Flow, including complex workflow design, custom UI components, and integration with external systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OI5WAM&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional Linux Operational Administrator Certification</a> - Confirms a candidate's proficiency in managing and administering Boomi on Linux systems, covering topics such as system installation, configuration, security, and performance optimization.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://community.boomi.com/s/learning-plan-detail-standard?ltui__urlRecordId=aOM6S0000008OIAWA2&amp;ltui__urlRedirect=learning-plan-detail-standard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Professional Windows Operational Administrator Certification</a> - Validates an individual's expertise in managing and administering Boomi on Windows systems, focusing on system installation, configuration, security, and performance optimization.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/training/certification/C0003107#exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Certified Solution Developer – App Connect Enterprise V11</a> - Validate your intermediate-level knowledge and experience to develop, deploy, tune, and support platform-independent message flow applications using IBM App Connect V11.0.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ibm.com/training/certification/C0002604#exam" rel="noopener noreferrer">IBM Certified Solution Implementer – API Connect v10.0.3</a> - Demonstrate your intermediate-level knowledge and skills to develop, publish, configure, and manage APIs using IBM API Connect v10.0.3.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gravitee.getlearnworlds.com/course/gravitee-event-native-api-management-foundations" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event-native API Management Foundations</a> - Basics of Event-native API Management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gravitee.getlearnworlds.com/course/gravitee-enap-certification" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event-native API Management Professional</a> - Focuses on some more advanced API Management concepts, plus foundational knowledge around how to use Gravitee API Management.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://konghq.com/academy/exam-preparation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kong Gateway Certified Associate</a> - Validate your entry-level knowledge and skills on Kong Gateway for developers, DevOps, and architects.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://training.mulesoft.com/certification/developer-mule4-level1" rel="noopener noreferrer">MuleSoft Certified Developer - Level 1</a> - Validate your knowledge and skills to design, build, test and debug, deploy, and manage basic APIs and integrations using MuleSoft.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://training.mulesoft.com/certification/developer-mule4-level2" rel="noopener noreferrer">MuleSoft Certified Developer - Level 2</a> - Validate your ability to work on production-ready Mule applications that address and balance critical non-functional requirements including monitoring, performance, maintainability, reliability, and security.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://training.mulesoft.com/certification/architect-integration-level1" rel="noopener noreferrer">MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect - Level 1</a> - Validate your knowledge and skills to translate functional and non-functional requirements into integration interfaces and implementations.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://training.mulesoft.com/certification/architect-platform-level1" rel="noopener noreferrer">MuleSoft Certified Platform Architect - Level 1</a> - Validate your knowledge and skills to direct the emergence of an effective application network out of individual integration solutions following API-led connectivity across an organization using Anypoint Platform.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://education.oracle.com/oracle-business-process-management-suite-12c-essentials/pexam_1Z0-435" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Business Process Management Suite 12c Certified Implementation Specialist</a> - Validate your expertise in implementing Oracle BPM Suite 12c solution.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://education.oracle.com/oracle-data-integrator-12c-certified-implementation-specialist/trackp_379" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle Data Integrator 12c Certified Implementation Specialist</a> - Validate your expertise in selling or implementing Oracle Data Integration 12c solutions.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://education.oracle.com/oracle-soa-suite-12c-essentials/pexam_1Z0-434" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle SOA Suite 12c Certified Implementation Specialist</a> - Validate your expertise in implementing solutions based on Oracle SOA Suite 12c.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/services/certification/red-hat-certified-specialist-api-management" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Certified Specialist in API Management</a> - Validates the ability to create and maintain enterprise APIs using the Red Hat 3scale API Management platform.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/services/certification/rhcs-business-rules" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Certified Specialist in Business Rules</a> - Checks the knowledge, skills, and abilities needed to perform tasks involving the implementation and management of business logic using the Red Hat JBoss BRMS.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/services/certification/rhcs-cloud-native-integration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Certified Specialist in Cloud-native Integration</a> - Validates the ability to create and maintain enterprise integration services based on Red Hat Fuse, Camel, and APIs.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/services/certification/red-hat-certified-specialist-event-driven-development-kafka" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Hat Certified Specialist in Event-Driven Development with Kafka</a> - Validates the ability to develop applications using Apache Kafka and Apache Kafka Streams.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://learn.snaplogic.com/snaplogic-administrator-certification" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Administrator Certification</a> - Assesses your ability to handle administrative tasks for SnapLogic instances.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://learn.snaplogic.com/snaplogic-architect-certification" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Architect Certification</a> - Evaluates your knowledge of integration reference architectures and key strategies for the SnapLogic platform, covering topics like SnapLogic Architecture, Snaplex Requirements, Pipeline Lifecycle Management, Advanced Data Transformations, API Management, Resumable Pipelines, and Best Practices.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://learn.snaplogic.com/snaplogic-developer-certification" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Developer Certification</a> - Testing your expertise in using the SnapLogic SDK, implementing different parts of Snap functionality, and building custom Snaps.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://learn.snaplogic.com/snaplogic-integrator-certification-1" rel="noopener noreferrer">SnapLogic Integrator Certification</a> - Focuses on topics such as beginner training, ultra tasks, pipeline migration, and user assistance videos covering various integration endpoints.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/19/"/>
    <summary>32 awesome projects updated on May 08 - May 14, 2023</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/16/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 17 - Apr 23, 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-04-17T13:21:14.000Z</updated>
    <published>2023-04-17T11:16:16.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Integration Patterns / Enterprise Integration Patterns</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Aggregator.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aggregator</a> - How do we combine the results of individual, but related messages so that they can be processed as a whole?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/CanonicalDataModel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Data Model</a> - How can you minimize dependencies when integrating applications that use different data formats?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ChannelAdapter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Channel Adapter</a> - How can you connect an application to the messaging system so that it can send and receive messages?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ChannelPurger.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Channel Purger</a> - How can you keep 'left-over' messages on a channel from disturbing tests or running systems?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/StoreInLibrary.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Claim Check</a> - How can we reduce the data volume of message sent across the system without sacrificing information content?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/CommandMessage.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Command Message</a> - How can messaging be used to invoke a procedure in another application?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/CompetingConsumers.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Competing Consumers</a> - How can a messaging client process multiple messages concurrently?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DistributionAggregate.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Composed Message Processor</a> - How can you maintain the overall message flow when processing a message consisting of multiple elements, each of which may require different processing?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DataEnricher.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Content Enricher</a> - How do we communicate with another system if the message originator does not have all the required data items available?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ContentFilter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Content Filter</a> - How do you simplify dealing with a large message, when you are interested only in a few data items?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ContentBasedRouter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Content-Based Router</a> - How do we handle a situation where the implementation of a single logical function (e.g., inventory check) is spread across multiple physical systems?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ControlBus.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Control Bus</a> - How can we effectively administer a messaging system that is distributed across multiple platforms and a wide geographic area?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/CorrelationIdentifier.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Correlation Identifier</a> - How does a requestor that has received a reply know which request this is the reply for?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DatatypeChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Datatype Channel</a> - How can the application send a data item such that the receiver will know how to process it?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DeadLetterChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dead Letter Channel</a> - What will the messaging system do with a message it cannot deliver?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Detour.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Detour</a> - How can you route a message through intermediate steps to perform validation, testing or debugging functions?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DocumentMessage.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Document Message</a> - How can messaging be used to transfer data between applications?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DurableSubscription.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Durable Subscriber</a> - How can a subscriber avoid missing messages while it is not listening for them?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/DynamicRouter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dynamic Router</a> - How can you avoid the dependency of the router on all possible destinations while maintaining its efficiency?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/EnvelopeWrapper.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Envelope Wrapper</a> - How can existing systems participate in a messaging exchange that places specific requirements on the message format, such as message header fields or encryption?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/EventMessage.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event Message</a> - How can messaging be used to transmit events from one application to another?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/EventDrivenConsumer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event-Driven Consumer</a> - How can an application automatically consume messages as they become available?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/FormatIndicator.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Format Indicator</a> - How can a message`s data format be designed to allow for possible future changes?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/GuaranteedMessaging.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Guaranteed Delivery</a> - How can the sender make sure that a message will be delivered, even if the messaging system fails?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/IdempotentReceiver.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Idempotent Receiver</a> - How can a message receiver deal with duplicate messages?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/InvalidMessageChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Invalid Message Channel</a> - How can a messaging receiver gracefully handle receiving a message that makes no sense?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Message.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message</a> - How can two applications connected by a message channel exchange a piece of information?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageDispatcher.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Dispatcher</a> - How can multiple consumers on a single channel coordinate their message processing?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageExpiration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Expiration</a> - How can a sender indicate when a message should be considered stale and thus shouldn`t be processed?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageTranslator.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Translator</a> - How can systems using different data formats communicate with each other using messaging?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageBroker.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Broker</a> - How can you decouple the destination of a message from the sender and maintain central control over the flow of messages?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageBus.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Bus</a> - What is an architecture that enables separate applications to work together, but in a decoupled fashion such that applications can be easily added or removed without affecting the others?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Channel</a> - How does one application communicate with another using messaging?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageEndpoint.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Endpoint</a> - How does an application connect to a messaging channel to send and receive messages?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Filter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Filter</a> - How can a component avoid receiving uninteresting messages?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageHistory.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message History</a> - How can we effectively analyze and debug the flow of messages in a loosely coupled system?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageRouter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Router</a> - How can you decouple individual processing steps so that messages can be passed to different filters depending on a set of conditions?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageSequence.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Sequence</a> - How can messaging transmit an arbitrarily large amount of data?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageStore.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Store</a> - How can we report against message information without disturbing the loosely coupled and transient nature of a messaging system?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessagingBridge.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Messaging Bridge</a> - How can multiple messaging systems be connected so that messages available on one are also available on the others?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessagingGateway.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Messaging Gateway</a> - How do you encapsulate access to the messaging system from the rest of the application?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessagingMapper.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Messaging Mapper</a> - How do you move data between domain objects and the messaging infrastructure while keeping the two independent of each other?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Normalizer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Normalizer</a> - How do you process messages that are semantically equivalent, but arrive in a different format?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/PipesAndFilters.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pipes and Filters</a> - How can we perform complex processing on a message while maintaining independence and flexibility?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/PointToPointChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Point-to-Point Channel</a> - How can the caller be sure that exactly one receiver will receive the document or perform the call?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/PollingConsumer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polling Consumer</a> - How can an application consume a message when the application is ready?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ProcessManager.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Process Manager</a> - How do we route a message through multiple processing steps when the required steps may not be known at design-time and may not be sequential?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/PublishSubscribeChannel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Publish-Subscribe Channel</a> - How can the sender broadcast an event to all interested receivers?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/RecipientList.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Recipient List</a> - How do we route a message to a list of dynamically specified recipients?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/RequestReply.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Request-Reply</a> - When an application sends a message, how can it get a response from the receiver?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Resequencer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Resequencer</a> - How can we get a stream of related but out-of-sequence messages back into the correct order?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/ReturnAddress.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Return Address</a> - How does a replier know where to send the reply?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/RoutingTable.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Routing Slip</a> - How do we route a message consecutively through a series of processing steps when the sequence of steps is not known at design-time and may vary for each message?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/BroadcastAggregate.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scatter-Gather</a> - How do you maintain the overall message flow when a message needs to be sent to multiple recipients, each of which may send a reply?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessageSelector.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Selective Consumer</a> - How can a message consumer select which messages it wishes to receive?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/MessagingAdapter.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Activator</a> - How can an application design a service to be invoked both via various messaging technologies and via non-messaging techniques?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/SmartProxy.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Smart Proxy</a> - How can you track messages on a service that publishes reply messages to the Return Address specified by the requestor?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Sequencer.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Splitter</a> - How can we process a message if it contains multiple elements, each of which may have to be processed in a different way?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/TestMessage.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Test Message</a> - What happens, though, if a component is actively processing messages, but garbles outgoing messages due to an internal fault?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/TransactionalClient.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Transactional Client</a> - How can a client control its transactions with the messaging system?</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/WireTap.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wire Tap</a> - How do you inspect messages that travel on a point-to-point channel?</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Integration Patterns / Integration Architecture Patterns</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chanakaudaya/solution-architecture-patterns/blob/master/vendor-neutral/API-led-Connectivity-Pattern.md" rel="noopener noreferrer">API-led Connectivity pattern (⭐3.4k)</a> - Use APIs to connect different systems and applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chanakaudaya/solution-architecture-patterns/blob/master/vendor-neutral/Anti-Corruption-Layer-Pattern.md" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anti Corruption Layer Pattern (⭐3.4k)</a> - Add a layer to isolate and transform data between systems.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chanakaudaya/solution-architecture-patterns/blob/master/vendor-neutral/Introduction-to-Change-Data-Capture.md" rel="noopener noreferrer">Change Data Capture Pattern (⭐3.4k)</a> - Capture and propagate changes made to a database or data source in real-time.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chanakaudaya/solution-architecture-patterns/blob/master/vendor-neutral/Hybrid-API-Management-Pattern.md" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hybrid API Management pattern (⭐3.4k)</a> - Manage APIs that span both cloud and on-premises environments using a central control plane.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chanakaudaya/solution-architecture-patterns/blob/master/vendor-neutral/Hybrid-Integration-Pattern.md" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hybrid Integration pattern (⭐3.4k)</a> - Integrate systems and applications that are deployed both on-premises and in the cloud using a combination of integration technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Integration Patterns / Microservice API Patterns</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Foundation<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/FrontendIntegration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Frontend Integration</a> - How can client-side end-user interfaces that are physically separated from server-side business logic and data storage be populated and updated with computing results, result sets from searches in data sources, and detailed information about data entities? How can application frontends invoke activities in a backend or upload data to it?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/BackendIntegration" rel="noopener noreferrer">Backend Integration</a> - How can distributed applications and their parts, which have been built independently and are deployed separately, exchange data and trigger mutual activity while preserving system-internal conceptual integrity without introducing undesired coupling?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/PublicAPI" rel="noopener noreferrer">Public API</a> - How can an API be made available to an unlimited and/or unknown number of API clients outside the organization that are globally, nationally, and/or regionally distributed?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/CommunityAPI" rel="noopener noreferrer">Community API</a> - How can the visibility of and the access to an API be restricted to a closed user group that does not work for a single organizational unit but for multiple legal entities (such as companies, nonprofit/nongovernment organizations, and governments)?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/SolutionInternalAPI" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solution-Internal API</a> - How can access to and usage of an API be limited to an application, for instance, components in the same or another logical layer and/or physical tier?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/foundation/APIDescription" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Description</a> - Which knowledge should be shared between an API provider and its clients? How should this knowledge be documented?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Responsibility<ul>
<li>Endpoint Roles<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/endpointRoles/ProcessingResource" rel="noopener noreferrer">Processing Resource</a> - How can an API provider allow its clients to trigger an action in it?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/endpointRoles/InformationHolderResource" rel="noopener noreferrer">Information Holder Resource</a> - How can domain data be exposed in an API, but its implementation still be hidden? How can an API expose data entities so that API clients can access and/or modify these entities concurrently without compromising data integrity and quality?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Operation Responsibilities<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/operationResponsibilities/StateCreationOperation" rel="noopener noreferrer">State Creation Operation</a> - How can an API provider allow its clients to report that something has happened that the provider needs to know about, for instance, to trigger instant or later processing?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/operationResponsibilities/RetrievalOperation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Retrieval Operation</a> - How can information available from a remote party (the API provider, that is) be retrieved to satisfy an information need of an end user or to allow further client-side processing?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/operationResponsibilities/StateTransitionOperation" rel="noopener noreferrer">State Transition Operation</a> - How can a client initiate a processing action that causes the provider-side application state to change? How can API clients and API providers share the responsibilities required to execute and control business processes and their activities?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/operationResponsibilities/ComputationFunction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Computation Function</a> - How can a client invoke side-effect-free remote processing on the provider side to have a result calculated from its input?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Information Holder Types<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/informationHolderEndpointTypes/OperationalDataHolder" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operational Data Holder</a> - How can an API support clients that want to create, read, update, and/or delete instances of domain entities that represent operational data: data that is rather short-lived, changes often during daily business operations, and has many outgoing relations?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/informationHolderEndpointTypes/MasterDataHolder" rel="noopener noreferrer">Master Data Holder</a> - How can I design an API that provides access to master data that lives for a long time, does not change frequently, and will be referenced from many clients?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/informationHolderEndpointTypes/ReferenceDataHolder" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reference Data Holder</a> - How should data that is referenced in many places, lives long, and is immutable for clients be treated in API endpoints? How can such reference data be used in requests to and responses from Processing Resources or Information Holder Resources?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/informationHolderEndpointTypes/LinkLookupResource" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link Lookup Resource</a> - How can message representations refer to other, possibly many and frequently changing, API endpoints and operations without binding the message recipient to the actual addresses of these endpoints?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/responsibility/informationHolderEndpointTypes/DataTransferResource" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Transfer Resource</a> - How can two or more communication participants exchange data without knowing each other, without being available at the same time, and even if the data has already been sent before its recipients became known?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Structure<ul>
<li>Representation Elements<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/representationElements/AtomicParameter" rel="noopener noreferrer">Atomic Parameter</a> - How can simple, unstructured data (such as a number, a string, a Boolean value, or a block of binary data) be exchanged between API client and API provider?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/representationElements/AtomicParameterList" rel="noopener noreferrer">Atomic Parameter List</a> - How can multiple related Atomic Parameters be combined in a representation element so that each of them stays simple, but their relatedness becomes explicit in the API Description and the runtime message exchanges?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/representationElements/ParameterTree" rel="noopener noreferrer">Parameter Tree</a> - How can containment relationships be expressed when defining complex representation elements and exchanging such related elements at runtime?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/representationElements/ParameterForest" rel="noopener noreferrer">Parameter Forest</a> - How can multiple Parameter Trees be exposed as request or response payload of an API operation?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Element Stereotypes<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/elementStereotypes/DataElement" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Element</a> - How can domain/application-level information be exchanged between API clients and API providers without exposing provider-internal data definitions in the API? How can API client and API provider be decoupled from a data management point of view?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/elementStereotypes/MetadataElement" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metadata Element</a> - How can messages be enriched with additional information so that receivers can interpret the message content correctly, without having to hardcode assumptions about the data semantics?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/elementStereotypes/IdElement" rel="noopener noreferrer">Id Element</a> - How can API elements be distinguished from each other at design time and at runtime? When applying domain-driven design, how can elements of the Published Language be identified?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/elementStereotypes/LinkElement" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link Element</a> - How can API endpoints and operations be referenced in request and response message payloads so that they can be called remotely?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Special Purpose Representations<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/specialPurposeRepresentations/APIKey" rel="noopener noreferrer">API Key</a> - How can an API provider identify and authenticate clients and their requests?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/specialPurposeRepresentations/ErrorReport" rel="noopener noreferrer">Error Report</a> - How can an API provider inform its clients about communication and processing faults? How can this information be made independent of the underlying communication technologies and platforms (for example, protocol-level headers representing status codes)?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/structure/specialPurposeRepresentations/ContextRepresentation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Context Representation</a> - How can API consumers and providers exchange context information without relying on any particular remoting protocols? How can identity information and quality properties in a request be made visible to related subsequent ones in conversations?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Quality<ul>
<li><p>Reference Management</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/referenceManagement/EmbeddedEntity" rel="noopener noreferrer">Embedded Entity</a> - How can one avoid sending multiple messages when their receivers require insights about multiple related information elements?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/referenceManagement/LinkedInformationHolder" rel="noopener noreferrer">Linked Information Holder</a> - How can messages be kept small even when an API deals with multiple information elements that reference each other?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Data Transfer Parsimony</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/dataTransferParsimony/Pagination" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pagination</a> - How can messages be kept small even when an API deals with multiple information elements that reference each other?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/dataTransferParsimony/WishList" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wish List</a> - How can an API client inform the API provider at runtime about the data it is interested in?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/dataTransferParsimony/WishTemplate" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wish Template</a> - How can an API client inform the API provider about nested data that it is interested in? How can such preferences be expressed flexibly and dynamically?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/dataTransferParsimony/ConditionalRequest" rel="noopener noreferrer">Conditional Request</a> - How can unnecessary server-side processing and bandwidth usage be avoided when frequently invoking API operations that return rarely changing data?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/dataTransferParsimony/RequestBundle" rel="noopener noreferrer">Request Bundle</a> - How can the number of requests and responses be reduced to increase communication efficiency?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Quality Management and Governance</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/qualityManagementAndGovernance/PricingPlan" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pricing Plan</a> - How can the API provider meter API service consumption and charge for it?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/qualityManagementAndGovernance/RateLimit" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rate Limit</a> - How can the API provider prevent API clients from excessive API usage?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/quality/qualityManagementAndGovernance/ServiceLevelAgreement" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Level Agreement</a> - How can an API client learn about the specific quality-of-service characteristics of an API and its endpoint operations? How can these characteristics, and the consequences of not meeting them, be defined and communicated in a measurable way?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Evolution<ul>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/VersionIdentifier" rel="noopener noreferrer">Version Identifier</a> - How can an API provider indicate its current capabilities as well as the existence of possibly incompatible changes to clients in order to prevent malfunctioning of clients due to undiscovered interpretation errors?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/SemanticVersioning" rel="noopener noreferrer">Semantic Versioning</a> - How can stakeholders compare API versions to detect immediately whether they are compatible?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/TwoInProduction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Two In Production</a> - How can a provider gradually update an API without breaking existing clients but also without having to maintain a large number of API versions in production?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/AggressiveObsolescence" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aggressive Obsolescence</a> - How can API providers reduce the effort for maintaining an entire API or its parts (such as endpoints, operations, or message representations) with guaranteed service quality levels?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/ExperimentalPreview" rel="noopener noreferrer">Experimental Preview</a> - How can providers make the introduction of a new API, or new API version, less risky for their clients and obtain early adopter feedback without having to freeze the API design prematurely?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/LimitedLifetimeGuarantee" rel="noopener noreferrer">Limited Lifetime Guarantee</a> - How can a provider let clients know for how long they can rely on the published version of an API?</li>
<li><a href="https://microservice-api-patterns.org/patterns/evolution/EternalLifetimeGuarantee" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eternal Lifetime Guarantee</a> - How can a provider support clients that are unable or unwilling to migrate to newer API versions at all?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Integration Patterns / SOA Patterns</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Foundational Inventory Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/canonical_protocol" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Protocol</a> - Defines a common communication protocol between services to enable interoperability and decoupling.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/canonical_schema" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Schema</a> - Defines a standard data model and format for exchanging data between services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/domain_inventory" rel="noopener noreferrer">Domain Inventory</a> - Identifies and categorizes the types of services within a particular domain.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/enterprise_inventory" rel="noopener noreferrer">Enterprise Inventory</a> - Identifies and categorizes the types of services within a particular domain.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/logic_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Logic Centralization</a> - Centralizes business logic within a service layer to reduce redundancy and promote consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_layers" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Layers</a> - Centralizes business logic within a service layer to reduce redundancy and promote consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_normalization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Normalization</a> - Centralizes business logic within a service layer to reduce redundancy and promote consistency.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Logical Inventory Layer Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/entity_abstraction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Entity Abstraction</a> - Abstracts data entities to simplify data access and reduce coupling.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/process_abstraction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Process Abstraction</a> - Abstracts processes to improve reusability and maintainability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/utility_abstraction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Utility Abstraction</a> - Abstracts common utilities to reduce duplication and promote consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/micro_task_abstraction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Micro Task Abstraction</a> - Breaks down tasks into smaller, more granular tasks for easier management.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Inventory Centralization Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/policy_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Policy Centralization</a> - Centralizes policies to reduce duplication and improve consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/process_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Process Centralization</a> - Centralizes processes to improve reusability and maintainability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/rules_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rules Centralization</a> - Centralizes business rules to reduce duplication and promote consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/schema_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Schema Centralization</a> - Centralizes data schemas to reduce duplication and improve consistency.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Inventory Implementation Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/canonical_resources" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Resources</a> - Defines a standard set of resources for common functionality across services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/cross_domain_utility_layer" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cross-Domain Utility Layer</a> - Uses multiple protocols for improved performance and flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/dual_protocols" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dual Protocols</a> - Defines a common utility layer across multiple domains.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/inventory_endpoint" rel="noopener noreferrer">Inventory Endpoint</a> - Defines a standard endpoint for accessing inventory resources.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_grid" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Grid</a> - Provides a framework for managing and scaling services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/state_repository" rel="noopener noreferrer">State Repository</a> - Stores and manages service state information.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/stateful_services" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stateful Services</a> - Maintains state information across service invocations.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/augmented_protocols" rel="noopener noreferrer">Augmented Protocols</a> - Enhances protocols with additional features.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Inventory Governance Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/canonical_expression" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Expression</a> - Defines a standard expression language for inventory data.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/canonical_versioning" rel="noopener noreferrer">Canonical Versioning</a> - Defines a standard versioning scheme for inventory resources.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/metadata_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metadata Centralization</a> - Centralizes metadata to reduce duplication and improve consistency.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Foundational Service Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/agnostic_capability" rel="noopener noreferrer">Agnostic Capability</a> - Abstracts service capabilities for improved flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/agnostic_context" rel="noopener noreferrer">Agnostic Context</a> - Abstracts service context for improved flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/functional_decomposition" rel="noopener noreferrer">Functional Decomposition</a> - Breaks down services into smaller, more manageable components.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/non_agnostic_context" rel="noopener noreferrer">Non-Agnostic Context</a> - Breaks down services into smaller, more manageable components.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_encapsulation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Encapsulation</a> - Encapsulates service functionality for improved maintainability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Implementation Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/partial_state_deferral" rel="noopener noreferrer">Partial State Deferral</a> - Encapsulates service functionality for improved maintainability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/partial_validation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Partial Validation</a> - Validates only relevant data for improved performance.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/redundant_implementation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Redundant Implementation</a> - Implements multiple versions of a service for improved flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_data_replication" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Data Replication</a> - Replicates data across multiple services for improved performance.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_facade" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Façade</a> - Provides a simplified interface to a complex service for improved usability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/ui_mediator" rel="noopener noreferrer">UI Mediator</a> - Mediates between the user interface and underlying services for improved usability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/reference_data_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reference Data Centralization</a> - Centralizes reference data to reduce duplication and improve consistency.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/microservice_deployment" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microservice Deployment</a> - Deploys services as independent, autonomous units for improved scalability and resilience.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/containerization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Containerization</a> - How can an environment be provided with maximum support for services with high-performance recovery and scalability requirements?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Security Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/exception_shielding" rel="noopener noreferrer">Exception Shielding</a> - Protects against security vulnerabilities through proper handling of exceptions.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/message_screening" rel="noopener noreferrer">Message Screening</a> - Screens messages for malicious content.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_perimeter_guard" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Perimeter Guard</a> - Guards the service perimeter to prevent unauthorized access.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/trusted_subsystem" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trusted Subsystem</a> - Establishes trust between subsystems for improved security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Contract Design Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/concurrent_contracts" rel="noopener noreferrer">Concurrent Contracts</a> - Allows multiple versions of a service contract to coexist simultaneously.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/contract_centralization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Contract Centralization</a> - Centralizes service contracts to improve consistency and reduce duplication.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/contract_denormalization" rel="noopener noreferrer">Contract Denormalization</a> - Centralizes service contracts to improve consistency and reduce duplication.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/decoupled_contract" rel="noopener noreferrer">Decoupled Contract</a> - Decouples service contracts from their implementation for improved flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/validation_abstraction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Validation Abstraction</a> - Abstracts validation logic to improve reusability and maintainability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Legacy Encapsulation Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/file_gateway" rel="noopener noreferrer">File Gateway</a> - Provides a gateway to access legacy file-based systems.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/legacy_wrapper" rel="noopener noreferrer">Legacy Wrapper</a> - Wraps legacy systems to expose them as services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/multi_channel_endpoint" rel="noopener noreferrer">Multi-Channel Endpoint</a> - Provides multiple communication channels to access legacy systems.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Governance Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/compatible_change" rel="noopener noreferrer">Compatible Change</a> - Enables changes to a service without breaking existing clients.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/decomposed_capability" rel="noopener noreferrer">Decomposed Capability</a> - Breaks down a service capability into smaller, more manageable pieces.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/distributed_capability" rel="noopener noreferrer">Distributed Capability</a> - Breaks down a service capability into smaller, more manageable pieces.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/proxy_capability" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proxy Capability</a> - Provides a proxy to a remote service capability to improve performance and reduce network overhead.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_decomposition" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Decomposition</a> - Breaks down a monolithic service into smaller, more manageable pieces.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_refactoring" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Refactoring</a> - Refactors a service to improve its design and performance.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/termination_notification" rel="noopener noreferrer">Termination Notification</a> - Notifies clients of a service's termination.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/version_identification" rel="noopener noreferrer">Version Identification</a> - Identifies the version of a service.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Capability Composition Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/capability_composition" rel="noopener noreferrer">Capability Composition</a> - Combines multiple service capabilities to create a new capability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/capability_recomposition" rel="noopener noreferrer">Capability Recomposition</a> - Recombines existing service capabilities to create a new capability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Messaging Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/asynchronous_queuing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Asynchronous Queuing</a> - Uses a message queue to decouple services and improve scalability and reliability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/event_driven_messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">Event-Driven Messaging</a> - Uses events to trigger service invocations and reduce coupling.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/intermediate_routing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Intermediate Routing</a> - Uses intermediate routing nodes to improve performance and flexibility.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/messaging_metadata" rel="noopener noreferrer">Messaging Metadata</a> - Uses metadata to describe and manage service messages.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/reliable_messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reliable Messaging</a> - Ensures message delivery and reliability in a distributed environment.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_agent" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Agent</a> - Acts as a proxy for a remote service to improve performance and reduce network overhead.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_callback" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Callback</a> - Uses callbacks to communicate between services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_instance_routing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Instance Routing</a> - Routes messages based on the service instance to improve performance and scalability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/service_messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">Service Messaging</a> - Describes the communication between services.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/state_messaging" rel="noopener noreferrer">State Messaging</a> - Uses messages to manage state information in a distributed environment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Composition Implementation Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/agnostic_sub_controller" rel="noopener noreferrer">Agnostic Sub-Controller</a> - Separates sub-controllers from the main controller to improve reusability and maintainability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/atomic_service_transaction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Atomic Service Transaction</a> - Uses transactions to ensure atomicity and consistency across multiple service invocations.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/compensating_service_transaction" rel="noopener noreferrer">Compensating Service Transaction</a> - Reverses the effects of a failed transaction.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/composition_autonomy" rel="noopener noreferrer">Composition Autonomy</a> - Enables services to act autonomously within a composition.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Service Interaction Security Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/brokered_authentication" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brokered Authentication</a> - Authenticates clients through a broker.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/data_confidentiality" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Confidentiality</a> - Ensures data confidentiality in a distributed environment.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/data_origin_authentication" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Origin Authentication</a> - Authenticates the origin of a message.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/direct_authentication" rel="noopener noreferrer">Direct Authentication</a> - Authenticates clients directly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>Transformation Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/data_format_transformation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Format Transformation</a> - Transforms data formats to enable interoperability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/data_model_transformation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Model Transformation</a> - Transforms data models to enable interoperability.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/protocol_bridging" rel="noopener noreferrer">Protocol Bridging</a> - Bridges between different protocols to enable interoperability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>REST-inspired Patterns<ul>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/entity_linking" rel="noopener noreferrer">Entity Linking</a> - Links related resources to enable navigation and discovery.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/lightweight_endpoint" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lightweight Endpoint</a> - Provides a lightweight endpoint for resource access.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/reusable_contract" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reusable Contract</a> - Reuses common contracts to improve consistency and reduce duplication.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/content_negotiation" rel="noopener noreferrer">Content Negotiation</a> - Negotiates the content format between clients and servers.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/endpoint_redirection" rel="noopener noreferrer">Endpoint Redirection</a> - Redirects clients to alternative endpoints.</li>
<li><a href="https://patterns.arcitura.com/soa-patterns/design_patterns/idempotent_capability" rel="noopener noreferrer">Idempotent Capability</a> - Ensures that the same action can be performed multiple times without changing the system state.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/16/"/>
    <summary>88 awesome projects updated on Apr 17 - Apr 23, 2023</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/15/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Apr 10 - Apr 16, 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-04-13T09:32:20.000Z</updated>
    <published>2023-04-12T12:22:13.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / API Specification</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/wsdl20" rel="noopener noreferrer">WSDL</a> - A powerful XML-based interface description language for SOAP-based services that enables software engineers to describe the functionality of a web service and automate the creation of client code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Data Formats</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bsonspec.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer">BSON</a> - Binary-encoded serialization format for JSON-like documents that is designed to be lightweight and efficient. It supports rich data types and is widely used in NoSQL databases, such as MongoDB.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc4180" rel="noopener noreferrer">CSV</a> - A simple and widely used data format that stores tabular data in plain text. It is easy to read and write, and can be processed by most programming languages.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8259" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSON</a> - A lightweight and easy-to-read data format that is widely used for data exchange. It supports a wide range of data types and is compatible with many programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Integration Styles</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/FileTransferIntegration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">File Transfer</a> - Data is exchanged through file exchange between applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/Messaging.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Messaging</a> - Applications exchange messages using a messaging infrastructure.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/EncapsulatedSynchronousIntegration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Remote Procedure Invocation</a> - Applications call functions or procedures on a remote server over a network.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/patterns/messaging/SharedDataBaseIntegration.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Shared Database</a> - Multiple applications access and manipulate the same data through a common database.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Protocols</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rabbitmq.com/resources/specs/amqp0-9-1.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer">AMQP 0-9-1</a> - A message queuing protocol that enables the exchange of messages between applications or systems. AMQP 0-9-1 provides reliability, security, and flexibility to handle complex messaging scenarios.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/amqp/core/v1.0/os/amqp-core-overview-v1.0-os.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">AMQP 1.0</a> - A widely accepted message queuing protocol that provides reliable, interoperable, and efficient messaging between systems. AMQP 1.0 supports a broad range of messaging scenarios and is ideal for complex enterprise-level applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://coap.technology/" rel="noopener noreferrer">CoAP</a> - A specialized application protocol designed for constrained devices in the Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystem. CoAP offers a lightweight, low-overhead communication mechanism to support resource-constrained devices.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.jsonrpc.org/specification" rel="noopener noreferrer">JSON-RPC</a> - A simple and lightweight remote procedure call protocol that enables communication between systems using JSON data. JSON-RPC offers stateless communication and is suitable for resource-constrained devices.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://mqtt.org/mqtt-specification/" rel="noopener noreferrer">MQTT</a> - A lightweight and efficient publish-subscribe protocol that supports messaging between devices. MQTT enables low-overhead communication and is ideal for IoT and mobile applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/soap/" rel="noopener noreferrer">SOAP</a> - A messaging protocol that uses XML to enable communication between systems. SOAP supports a wide range of messaging scenarios, including distributed computing and enterprise applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://stomp.github.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer">STOMP</a> - A messaging protocol that offers simple, text-oriented communication between systems. STOMP is ideal for low-latency, high-performance messaging scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Standard APIs</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/technotes/guides/jdbc/" rel="noopener noreferrer">JDBC</a> - A Java-based API that provides universal data access to relational databases. JDBC offers a consistent and efficient way to access and manipulate data, making it a popular choice among developers.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://javaee.github.io/jms-spec/" rel="noopener noreferrer">JMS</a> - A messaging API that enables Java applications to send and receive messages. JMS supports reliable messaging and is widely used in enterprise-level applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/odbc/reference/odbc-overview" rel="noopener noreferrer">ODBC</a> - A widely accepted API that provides a standardized way to access data from various database management systems. ODBC offers a consistent interface to access data, making it easy to develop database applications.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.odata.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer">OData</a> - An open protocol that enables the creation and consumption of queryable and interoperable REST APIs. OData simplifies the development of REST APIs and offers a standardized way to access data.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Structure and Validation</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.schematron.com" rel="noopener noreferrer">Schematron</a> - A rule-based validation language that enables developers to define and validate business rules, data reporting, quality control, and other validation scenarios. Schematron offers a flexible way to validate XML documents.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema11-1/" rel="noopener noreferrer">XML Schema</a> - A schema language that offers facilities for describing the structure and constraining the contents of XML documents. XML Schema enables developers to ensure that XML data conforms to a specific structure, making it easier to process and manipulate.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2023/15/"/>
    <summary>21 awesome projects updated on Apr 10 - Apr 16, 2023</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/41/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Oct 11 - Oct 17, 2021</title>
    <updated>2021-10-12T14:49:24.000Z</updated>
    <published>2021-10-12T14:49:24.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Market Analysis</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>iPaaS<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/434187" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Critical Capabilities for Enterprise Integration Platform as a Service</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/397953" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Magic Quadrant for Enterprise Integration Platform as a Service</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.forrester.com/report/the-forrester-wave-tm-enterprise-ipaas-q4-2021/RES176201" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Forrester Wave: Enterprise iPaaS</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/41/"/>
    <summary>1 awesome projects updated on Oct 11 - Oct 17, 2021</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/34/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Aug 23 - Aug 29, 2021</title>
    <updated>2021-08-26T10:58:14.000Z</updated>
    <published>2021-08-26T10:58:14.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Market Analysis</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>API Management<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/468184" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Critical Capabilities for Full Life Cycle API Management</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/464116" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Magic Quadrant for Full Life Cycle API Management</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.forrester.com/go?objectid=RES159081" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Forrester Wave: API Management Solutions</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>RPA<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/465756" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Critical Capabilities for Robotic Process Automation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/441474" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Magic Quadrant for Robotic Process Automation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.forrester.com/go?objectid=RES161538" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Forrester Wave: Robotic Process Automation</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/34/"/>
    <summary>2 awesome projects updated on Aug 23 - Aug 29, 2021</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/30/</id>
    <title>Awesome Integration Updates on Jul 26 - Aug 01, 2021</title>
    <updated>2021-07-27T04:06:00.000Z</updated>
    <published>2021-07-26T03:47:47.000Z</published>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><p>Resources / Articles</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/enterpriseREST.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Enterprise Integration Using REST</a> - Discusses the constraints and flexibility that you have with nonpublic APIs, and lessons learned from doing large scale RESTful integration across multiple teams.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/richardsonMaturityModel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer">Richardson Maturity Model</a> - Explained by Martin Fowler, originally presented by Leonard Richardson.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Connectors</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://projects.eclipse.org/projects/ee4j.jca" rel="noopener noreferrer">JCA</a> - Defines a standard architecture for Jakarta EE application components to connect to Enterprise Information Systems. Formerly Java EE Connector Architecture and J2EE Connector Architecture.</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/#connect" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kafka Connect</a> - A tool for scalably and reliably streaming data between Apache Kafka and other systems.</li>
</ul>
<h3><p>Resources / Market Analysis</p>
</h3>
<ul>
<li>BPM<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/292486" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Critical Capabilities for Intelligent Business Process Management Suites</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/345694" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Magic Quadrant for Intelligent Business Process Management Suites</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li>ETL<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/464068" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Critical Capabilities for Data Integration Tools</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gartner.com/doc/code/450251" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner Magic Quadrant for Data Integration Tools</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.trackawesomelist.com/2021/30/"/>
    <summary>6 awesome projects updated on Jul 26 - Aug 01, 2021</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>